They were ordered to provide hope...
The Six Triple Eight is a drama, war, history film directed by Tyler Perry.
During World War II, the US Army's only all-Black, all-women battalion takes on an impossible mission: sorting through a three-year
backlog of 17 million pieces of mail that hadn't been delivered to American soldiers and finish within six months.
Charity Adams, played by Kerry Washington.
Franklin Delano Roosevelt, played by Sam Waterston.
Eleanor Roosevelt, played by Susan Sarandon.
General Halt, played by Dean Norris.
Mary McLeod Bethune, played by Oprah Winfrey.
Lena Derriecott King, played by Ebony Obsidian.
The Six Triple Eight is a 2024 American war drama film written and directed by Tyler Perry on the 6888th
Central Postal Directory Battalion, an all-black, all-female battalion, in World War II.
It is based on the article "Fighting a Two-Front War" by Kevin M.
The film's ensemble cast includes Kerry Washington, Ebony Obsidian, Milauna Jackson, Shanice Shantay, Sarah Jeffery, Pepi
Sonuga, Gregg Sulkin, Susan Sarandon, Dean Norris, Sam Waterston, Kylie Jefferson, Moriah Brown, and Oprah Winfrey.
The Six Triple Eight had a limited theatrical release on December 6,
2024, then began airing on Netflix on December 20.
The film received mixed reviews from critics.
Its song, "The Journey", was nominated for Best
Original Song at the 97th Academy Awards.
The film was nominated for and won five awards at the 56th NAACP Image Awards, including
Outstanding Motion Picture and acting wins for Washington, Obsidian, and the ensemble cast.
The film explores themes of world war ii, based on true story,
historical, military, based on magazine, newspaper or article.
The tone is emotional.